### Contact

colinnebula@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/colinnebula-07176022 (LinkedIn) colinnebula.github.io/colin-reactportfolio/ (Portfolio) colinnebula3dartist.blogspot.ca (Portfolio)

### Top Skills

Document Object Model (DOM) Node.js MongoDB

### Languages

French

# Colin Nebula

3D Animation Artist / VFX / Rotoscoping

Toronto, Ontario, Canada

# Summary

I have the time commitment required, but also the experience to properly complete the requirements of the job that has a high demand for strong design and technical skills.

As a 2D/3D artist and Full-Stack developer, I am adept at the following: Blender, Autodesk Maya, Zbrush, Adobe Creative Suit, as well as React, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, JavaScript in conjunction with other software, all utilized to get the project done on time. I am a fast learner and am capable of adapting to situations or client requests as I have done so in all my prior positions.

I possess classical 2D art experience as well as 3D modeling, animation experience and would love to be part your team. Having previously worked with companies like Intelligent Creatures, I understand the pipeline well.

# Experience

Nebula Media.ca Creative Director August 2013 - April 2017 (3 years 9 months) Woodbridge Ontario

- A host of responsibilities including but not limited to overseeing video production, 3D integration, and video editing including Soccer instructional videos with late Olympian Tony Waiters' World of Soccer
- Discussed, planned, executed, and met client requirements including timely deadlines
- Primarily used Adobe Creative Suite and Blender; sound incorporation and integrating 3D objects

 Worked independently and remotely mostly for clients dispersed over Canada and the US

#### Partsmart

Technical Support Consultant December 2011 - 2012 (1 year)

Richmond Hill

- Network/Desktop support consultant with hardware and software application support, connectivity, and running reports to ensure smooth flow of operations for daily tasks
- Manage software licenses, maintain connections, troubleshoot hardware/ software issues
- Perform regular maintenance such as installations, updates, firewalls, virus protection,

OS setups and exceeding requirements in making the systems user-friendly for employees

### Intelligent Creatures

Intern

September 2010 - November 2010 (3 months)

- Modelling/Texturing
- VFX responsibilities (compositing, rotoscoping, etc.)
- TV Commercials
- TV Shows

#### **Tira Wireless**

Quality Assurance - Mobile Game Platform

August 2007 - July 2008 (1 year)

Toronto

 Tested and logged bugs, addressed issues through JIRA workflow manager, conducted

field tests, regressions, developed strategies to reduce redundancies, and completed

general QA duties such as running reports and assisting the team in hitting weekly targets

 Set up a rotating schedule to improve team efficiency by assigning equipment for specific

periods to each team member to reduce dead time and exceed weekly testing targets

Clients included companies such as Sony, ING, Hudson Soft, THQ,
 AccuWeather, each
 with specific demands and multiple unique requests to account for in testing scenarios

Epson Printing
Technical Support-Inbound Call Centre
December 2003 - January 2005 (1 year 2 months)
Richmond Hill

- Provided troubleshooting for the complete product line, resolved complaints, ordered replacements for customers in a timely manner while up-selling other Epson products
- Conducted weekly reports, solved issues that required multi-department input and introduced ideas such as empowering the group with more tools to resolve complaints
- Maintained top performance numbers for accuracy and commended for punctuality

Advanced Brake Products
Computer Technician
June 2003 - August 2004 (1 year 3 months)
Toronto

- Set up multiple office computers and connected them to the network to share office
- resources such as inventory systems, billings, production, and multiple sets of printers
- Provided considerable support in training and preparing staff for tasks on the new
- systems as well as set up security to prevent damage or loss of valuable information
- Performed routine tasks to keep the network and individual workstations problem-free

and was responsible for all software and hardware issues experienced by staff

## Education

University of Toronto Coding Bootcamp

Certificate, Web Development · (May 2021 - November 2021)

Centennial College

Digital Animation, Maya, 3DS Max, Zbrush, Fusion, Nuke, Photoshop, Live Drawing  $\cdot$  (2009 - 2010)

# Art Institute of Toronto

2D Art and 3D Game Design, Life drawing, 3DS Max, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Torque Game Engine  $\cdot$  (2005 - 2007)